Good morning. Good morning, Chris, how are you?
Good, thanks. Um,
I rescheduled this as our regular EOC quality touchpoint, and Chris, I invited Andy and Erin Royer to join us, because they've been doing some peripheral work as well. I think you've probably had some contact with each of them.
And I thought to eliminate any kind of confusion or dual workflows, let's just all come together.
in our touch points, so I've added them to the invite as optional moving forward.
Um, so that we're all on the same page.
Okay.
Um, I know that Andy had shared a few weeks ago the list of, um,
updated measures and, uh, shared also that she had submitted an updated rhythm
Uh, so that these measures would be routed to you, Chris. Um, so I wanted to check in on the status of you, you know, receiving the data for those measures.
Yeah, so we don't have it yet, um, but we will soon. They were added
to, um… they were added to be released into the table, I guess. I don't know the…
I don't know the mechanics of it.
But the person who runs that, Myra Church, her team,
she did the work directly, so we… I set up a meeting with her,
And I… off the top of my head, I don't know what was added, but I sent a message… let me just check.
Yeah, I have one… I included in the invite, and it's so small, I don't know how to blow it up in the invite.
Let's see… um…
I don't know if anybody else knows how to do this.
If you can zoom in on it.
Um, sorry, are you talking to me? I'm just talking in general. Oh, okay, I thought you were asking me to do something. No, so I knew…
I think you had shared one that lists… it starts with GI Screen AD, so screening colonoscopy adenoma detection rate, and then…
under that GI AFU, the appropriate follow-up interval for normal colonoscopy.
And then OS, SSI, surgical site infection, OSFS lumbar, functional status after lumbar surgery,
AMM antidepressant medication management, and then endoscopy.
Barrett's esophagus, and then the THATKA risk.
So, those last two had still…
TBD under their, um…
you know, status. I think, Chris, on the one that you sent me, and then…
When you said they…
Who do you mean when you say they there?
Um, Andy. Like today, we… okay.
Andy. Got it.
Yeah, so with this list here…
We might have missed… I'm looking at the list right now.
In the invite? Yeah.
And then I think the one on the right is the one that Andy sent me. It also includes the NTSV and C-section rate. I know I've…
Um, so I didn't have all of the ones, um…
you know, for the…
surgical site infection and functional status when I had spoken to you and Tamaris, you know, a couple months ago, I didn't have those, so…
This was helpful for me. I… sorry, I'm looking… I know what you're talking about now, I'm looking, so…
And I can share my screen, but it's just so tiny, I don't know if any of you have a… No, I've got it. I've got it here, so I'm good, so let me just…
take a look.
So, the two…
The two images, some are…
a lot of these are duplicated. The difference being…
What's the difference here? Sure. On the left, um, I didn't have the measure ID for endoscopy Barrett's esophagus, and THATKA.
Um, and the left one, I received the measure, and I… again, it's, like, really confusing how to get any information,
of, like, what this is coming from. I don't have a view into Cognizant, so Elias Daraj from our team,
um, pulled the measure ID, so that's why they said still TBD on the left side. And then on the right side, I just am acknowledging that PCO2 and SMM have been available in some form or fashion for years.
And they've just been going back and forth, including, um,
trying to find additional data sources to make those more accurate, etc., so I thought it was a little bit…
Um, in order to be comprehensive, I should include them in as well, but you see on the bottom of…
Um, this… the one on the right, it has, like, the…
the measure ID for Barrett's esophagus, THATKA, and then I threw in those two.
Um, measure IDs that have been
coming through Cognizant with varying levels of completeness.
for a long time. Um, just because I know that those are also part of the program.
Yes. So…
I know that PCO2 and SMM are
going to be available on the next rerun. I can find out exactly when that is.
Um,
So what we were told, um,
Cognizant delivered all of the other ones, um, in varying months over the past several
quarters since Erin had requested them.
But what we were told was,
That we needed to wait until MLQM switched to the new year, which it's doing right now, between, um,
April to June, they switch over to the new year, which is… they're using the NY2025 software.
That should align with the, um,
with the measure IDs here, and as you said, Chris, Myra…
I had to take it to Myra's team, and they downloaded it,
Then, when I was talking to Surrendra and Roman on Myra's team, they were like, well, you know, we don't query for any of these measure IDs.
Um, because, like, I'm not putting them into an ACO scorecard or anything.
So that's when…
I came to understand that I should have…
connected with you and Myra.
somehow differently, so that's why I put in a new rhythm.
Okay. So you can tell how vague I am, because I don't really understand what I'm saying.
Yeah, and I kind of understand a little bit of it, and that's on me, because I don't know Myra's end of it, and she's pretty close to me, so I can find that information out to
see where the gap is. So, and, like, for the rest of these, to find out when
And how. PCO2 and SMM, I know.
Uh, the others… I… I can figure it out. And I'll ping her.
Like, right after we get out of here. Okay, and then, I mean, Aaron, AMM24 is on here. I feel like that's probably to do with…
Another request, but I don't know, I…
Yeah, that was for, um, the behavioral health.
pay for performance model that we were working on last year. Um…
I mean, I… right now, it's not on our shortlist for the model that we're developing this year as a part of our corrective action plan.
if it's… if it's worth us testing,
to see performance in it, just to see if it's worth keeping, or…
removing, um, maybe, maybe that would be a worthwhile exercise, just to see if it is worth
considering for this model?
Sure. So I can remove that from this list here, from the episode of Care People, and I can just follow up, Erin, with you and Myra.
Because Surrender already has it in the MLQM.
So, and then, Chris, I don't really understand how Episode of Care, um, is building.
the reports. The reason that the… and sorry if this is…
all known knowledge. But the reason that the ACO and PCMH is all coming through
Um, MLQM is because we are agnostic of what type of commercial insurance anybody has.
For a regulatory HEDIS for our regular, like, we have to report on timely cancer screen.
screenings or diabetes care, or whatever.
Um, we are required by the, um, accrediting body to split out our commercial membership into HMO and PPO and legal entity and whatever.
Um, but if we're talking for a provider-facing, value-based program, like, we do not care if
if people have CareFirst HMO or CareFirst PPO, or CareFirst GHMSI, and that's why, um, um, the MLQM
that's why all of this quality performance is routed through MLQM, but I don't know…
I got a little confused about, um,
how that interacts or doesn't with the episode of Care program.
Yep, so we… we, um…
basically joined together the information from H-metrics.
with the… with data in MLQM for that member.
And if they have one of these measures,
we link it to the episode.
And… you know that it's…
through a number of different ways, like member ID, dates…
And then that information is, you know, pulled into… for the EOC reports.
Sorry, the main thing is we get the numerator and denominator.
From there.
Okay.
is that make sense, or…?
Yeah, so I think that we still did need
Myra's team to download the measure IDs from Cognizant, but then…
Yeah, we do. Okay. Because they need to… they need to be output into MLQM.
Okay. Well, great.
And here's the thing. So, did… so they already did that?
Yes. Okay, and did they say that the data would flow through?
I don't… I can… on these measures…
Like, if they did the download, does that mean… I don't know what that means, that…
I don't know if that means that simply downloading or whatever they're doing will…
enable the data to get into the table I need.
I don't know that either. So, yeah, okay, I could check.
My understanding is that it wouldn't have been in any of the 2025 data. It wouldn't have been available in any of the 2025 data, so they…
um, queried it from Cognizant and pulled it into MLQM, whatever that means.
Um, for the 2026 data, which…
I haven't seen published yet, but I think that they are…
working on it. What have I? I've heard that it's, like, in the computed layer, I don't know what that means.
But I've heard a few people reference that.
You can speak, Aaron, you don't need to raise your hand.
Sorry, I just didn't want to interrupt your train of thought. Is there a reason why 2025 data wasn't pulled, just in case we need to have, like,
historical performance as a way to set a target for providers? Yeah, for benchmarking.
Yeah. I don't know the answer to that.
I was told when it was available by Cognizant that, um,
I mean, I submitted the ticket at that time, and I don't know if it was because they were all focusing on, you know, finishing out 2025 through Q1 of
2026, or, um…
that they weren't going to pull it into scorecards in 2025, so they were just gonna start fresh in 2026.
Um, but that's, uh…
question of, like, ticket prioritization.
that I can… I can ask them again.
And just say, like, you know, since it's been available for
5 or 6 months in some instances. I think the reason I didn't have a measure ID for the Barrett's esophagus is because that one is newly available.
Um, but for the other ones, they've been available since…
Um, like, December and February.
Um, and so…
yeah, I don't know. Of this year.
December or February of this year. February of this year, yeah, and December of 25. Of last year, right.
So, I, as well, noticed that there is no 2000…
6 data… 2026 data in the table I need.
So, I chalk that up to that it will be there soon, and that's what…
Her run is going now.
Yeah, and at that time, these measure IDs should be there. Now, I don't know, like,
with, um, like, PCO2 as an example, when it was delivered, then
And we pulled it through, and…
Um, then Roman was able to show me how it was showing up in the MLQM data tables,
the, um, the C-section rate was nonsense. It was…
Um, and the point of the NTSV is to locate for, um,
lower… I mean, lower risk.
I think it's similar to the, like, LRCD low-risk cesarean delivery, um, so it should be much lower.
then our, um…
altogether wholesale C-section rate, and it wasn't. It was 36%. And so…
Um, it was difficult to, like, drill into the data, um, further and kind of, um,
kind of sanity check it. So, I don't know if we'll experience something similar with these new measures, but once again, like, I haven't seen them.
I will tell you, there were a couple of other, and this is off-topic from your episode of CARE meeting, but, um, the Account Insights people really wanted to see a couple of other quality measure.
Removing the continuous enrollment requirement.
And I saw those within the, um…
within the HEDIS tables at Cognizant.
And so, um,
And, you know, they were working as I expected. I expected our call on, like, a colorectal cancer screening rate to be, um, higher for…
Um, are continuously enrolled people than it is for our, um, our whole population, and it was… so all of that was functioning correctly, and I was able to see that in…
the cognizant tables. Um…
And that just sort of happenstance.
Because I don't normally have access to the cognizant tables.
Yeah, and that's good to know. I would say…
Because the HEDIS team and Myra's quality team are adjacent to…
the team I work on, and…
if it's available there,
It's usually something we can… we can get. We just need to know
what it is. So those, you know, whatever those values are that you have here.
Um, and then, I guess the other point I want to make is
in something you said that
If there is, like, if the output of one of these is not
quality in any sense that you…
would want, um…
you know, that will flow through.
to the dashboard, unless we do something additional
in the code to compensate or remove.
Say that again?
So… I think you're saying in a more specific way, like, um, the quality of what is put in will equal the quality of what is generated. So if it's not aligning, like, to your point around the, um…
NTSV, Andy looking equal to our book of business rate.
Um, for total C-section.
what… I think what Chris is saying is that we'll have to co…
identify what's driving that encode
Around that? To fix it, so that we have a more accurate reflection of what the true NTSV is.
But I think we need to see data before we can do that, Chris, and QA it.
Sure. Yep, totally.
Yeah, and that, I think, um,
Erin, I think you've brought this up several times, but that is one of the, um, challenges with Cognizant as the vendor, is that they are a little bit, um…
you know, hold the… the code that they put.
They don't share that, so it is a little bit of…
trial and error to figure out if
If the rates don't look correct, but like I said, for some of the other ones that I did see, so I gave you the kind of negative example of PCO2 measure, but
For these other no continuous enrollment, they were functioning as expected. They slightly increased the denominator, they…
radically reduced our compliance rate, like, that's all… all things that I was expecting. So I also have, um…
a positive example therein. So, um…
Yeah, that's great. That's very good.
Um, but yeah, I… I, um…
If there are other pieces of information that we can provide, um, in service of this request, let… let me know.
So, just to confirm, what is the final list?
That, of these, that is…
that you are requesting? Well, it's all of these besides AMM24.
So, I think that… You should be removing…
AMM24. Yeah, and in the rhythm, I added in
the, um…
G-I-B-E-S, and I added in the measure IDs in the comments of the rhythm.
Okay, let me ask a question as well, though, because Erin,
Aren't there additional measures for the maternity ladder that I don't see reflected here?
And maybe that's okay, maybe we're already getting the data, and that's why. But, um, what about the, um, prenatal and postpartum, um, depression screening?
And the immunizations.
So, since those are already HEDIS measures, um, they don't need to be pulled from Cognizant separately, but they do need to be pulled into the…
dashboard when it's time, yeah.
Okay, and I think I've shared those with Chris and Tamaris previously. I just want to make sure, like, we should actually have kind of a source of truth that says, these are all the measures, these are the ones that are currently flowing through through HEDIS,
These are the ones that…
you know, we need…
ASAP.
Yeah, I mean…
kind of one list, and then we can…
Because the status might be different for each, so…
to maintain that is a good idea.
I guess I had a thought…
Um…
Oh, the one, the…
the pregnancy, the prenatal,
all these… sorry, I'm scrolling blank on what exactly.
And… do you remember the names or the values for those?
Sure, do you mean the… but you mean the measure ID? We just… yeah, if you could just tell me the values, like the name, just because I kind of remember the code.
And I just want to say…
if… if it's in there.
Okay, yeah, Colleen, if you have, and… or Erin, if you guys have, um, which measures these are,
Um, I will check… the only reason I would check is that, um,
PRSE and PPC, um,
like, PBC, I feel pretty confident, remains. PPC1 and PPC2 for prenatal and postpartum care.
Um, but the PRSE, every once in a while, because it's two immunizations, flu and Tdap,
Um, and then, um, like, at least on my team, we always report the combination, um, but anyway, the submeasures in MLQM,
Mostly stay the same year over year, but I would just want to triple check.
Because, like, you know, they changed the A1C measure ID, like, 7 times in the past.
Um, several years, and every time,
it messes with our MLQM codes just a little bit. And you… and just to clarify, you are saying that that's something I should be checking, because that is done
in the cognitive process, and then is reflected in MLQM.
Yeah, I mean… But any changes, because Myra would own that.
Yeah, if your code suddenly returns zero…
Yeah. And then… then…
It doesn't mean that there's no pregnant people, it likely means that they added an underscore into the measure ID.
Yep. Yeah, so… That happened with us in the A1C measure the other day. We were… our PCMH thing was looking weird, and, you know, they… and…
Aleem knew, she reached out to me and was like, what's going on? And we dug through the measure crosswalk, and they added a hyphen or something.
Okay, so I didn't… I guess I did not know that you worked… have worked with her team.
a good bid on this.
and probably know a lot more than me.
into what they actually are doing.
Yeah, but like I said, um, I really appreciate, um,
everyone's patience, because this… because specific to the new measures that are going to be so impactful, or, like, at least more germane
Colleen, to your program, and that you and Erin have pushed, um, I… my success rate with
Getting them from Cognizant into a scorecard is middling, and so I appreciate everyone's patience as we figure out how to route our requests
efficiently and correctly.
Yeah, um… you know, definitely, you know, this has been a, you know, labor of, you know, love for, you know, many years, I think.
I started this process in 21 with the NTSV and SMM.
Um, and I want to make sure, like, if we're doing it, we're, you know, sharing accurate information, so I appreciate your diligence and your partnership here, Andy. I know it's been going on a long time, and everybody, really.
Um, I hope that as we are figuring this out, that we can also document the
true process that's working, and develop an SOP from this, so that it's repeatable. And when we go to adjust for, you know, additional measures as we scale our program, we're not recreating the wheel and spending another, you know, 5 years trying to get a new measure added.
And I know much of that 5 years wasn't…
the five of us on the phone here, but if we can figure out together how to navigate the more technical side,
then maybe we can do that in a, you know, much more condensed timeframe.
Yeah, so this is what I think on that. I think that's a really good idea.
And what I'm going to do is audit the current code for what it is looking for, and then drop that into a…
spreadsheet, and then also add what is now newly coming in.
And then sending that over, so we have one source, and maybe… I don't know where we want to store it,
Or who wants to own it, but we can start there. And then…
Make sure everything is kind of included that we want, and then we can, you know, at the same time, we could be looping in Myra.
And then we can develop… start to develop an SOP around that kind of being where we go to.
across, you know, between…
your side and my side to see what's going on.
That's perfect, and I see Erin put in the chat, yes, we should definitely be storing this in the payment transformation shared folder on the S drive. Um, and I believe that there's a folder in there already, uh, labeled Quality. Um… Okay.
So, you know, we can identify… Erin and I, the appropriate repository and share that pathway with this team. So, Chris, that sounds like a great idea, auditing the current code.
I know we only have a couple minutes left, so I'm gonna… I know you said a few things you were gonna check with Myra, one of them being, um,
some gaps currently exist with the new measurement year in MLQM. You're going to query that with her, as well as, um,
you know, what… how they did the download, and if this means it will feed into your table.
Um, and then you'll also do auditing of the current code for what's coming in.
Um, and I just checked with Sondra, because I had asked him, um, last week for the, like, official final measure ID,
And… directory, and he says that that should be available by early next week. So when that is available, I will send over
I was writing you, like, here's what the measure IDs should definitely be for 2026, um, and I need
to wait until I…
get that, um, directory from Sondra. So I'll send that over into this team chat, or, um…
when I have it next… early next week.
So what Surrendra is, um, providing you is the measure IDs.
Yeah, so the ones that I put in that screenshot should be correct.
Um, for the new measures. Um, I just…
I raised that slight, uh,
anxiety about… specifically about the PRSE measure, to be honest with you, but also the PDS, like, screening, they always are adding something like underscore total or whatever, and I just want to make sure that I'm…
Um, giving you the precise information for that, um, for when Chris does that check.
Okay. And, um, I have the… I have the 2025 version of it, but like I said, they're gonna switch it over.
Um, and he… and so I just said that Director will be available next… early next week, so I will turn that into this chat at that time.
Thank you. And then Erin and I can connect offline and make sure. I think I already have the comprehensive list of measures. We will review it together, and then
I will email that to this group, so we're all working from the same understanding.
Um, and then…
I'm going to shift tack real quick, because I know we only have 3 minutes left.
Chris and Tamaris, I am…
uh… including the two of you in the email, um…
Shane, and Erin, you're in this as well already. Uh, we are looking to
go to governance for approval to resume pushing data to Hmetrics. I'm going to be sending you the
fields from the standard data file, um, and you will see, um, the ones
that we have excluded, highlighted in red. If the two of you can review those lists,
of fields for our enrollment files, our medical files, and our pharmacy files to make sure
I'm not removing any information that the two of you need to, um, pull in the quality information.
Um, I think you took a cursory look back in maybe the December timeframe, uh,
It's been a few months since we've, you know, touched it, and I have to submit a brand new one-stop-and-start from scratch for this H-metric process, so…
please be on the lookout for that, and if you could review it and get back to me as soon as possible, I'd appreciate it.
Yes, just to confirm, we… we did look at this. I think… I think you shared screen.
And went through this, um, so I… we… I will review.
make sure. But, like,
It's just, like, name and date of birth… what… it's name? Yeah, it's like… it's, you know, it's a lot of fields, but it's, like, member life ID, group 2, we're excluding group 1, 3, and 4.
Um, so there are some information that aren't just basic demographic.
So,
that… that is go… that is going to be going forward.
Yes. Once in the new… when you sign the new contract, or whatever you do with H-metrics to begin the flow again, it's gonna… the data's gonna be coming through with those
with less those fields identified.
Correct. Okay. And that is because, um,
When Zach Maurer was here in Actuary, he…
And Matt identified there was a lot of duplicates in the files that were coming through, and it was skewing the data.
And in reviewing that, Zach identified we're sending way too much PHI. That's not necessary, so we went through and tried to make a thoughtful
Um, you know, excluding the fields that really aren't relevant to what is being captured in the grouper, and I want to make sure that I'm not
unknowingly excluding fields that you need for quality reporting.
Yes, okay, I remember more clearly now, and I… the reason I asked for clarification is I had, like, a low confidence.
that I knew what was going on there, but now remembering our review, I guess I thought that they were excluding member life ID altogether, and I was like, well, how would that work?
But it's not from all files. That's what the thing was. It was for certain files, removing what wasn't necessary for them.
Thanks, Erin. Yeah, so we're keeping Member Life ID, but we're removing, like,
there are fields called, like, old member life ID and old card number, so those fields are getting excluded, and you'll see, I have it broken out.
Um, by field label. Um…
For each one. So, just review that. It's not, like, hundreds of rows. It's, like, I don't know, 20-ish rows.
Each. Um…
So just take a look at it, let me know if you have questions. Happy to respond either.
Jumping back on a call or pinging.
Okay, did you send that as an email, or is that just in the chat?
Um, I am going to send an email.
Okay, that's… I have it… I have it kind of, um, pulled up and drafted, um, but I lost
power yesterday afternoon, so I couldn't complete it. Um, so I just need to kind of review it and
you know, refresh from yesterday afternoon to make sure I'm not sending out an incomplete email.
Okay, and once you send it, I will take a look at it to get that… to turn that around for you.
Fantastic, I appreciate it. And then,
you know, I know we're at time, so, um, let's just kind of, like, have on the radar. I know that the two of you were working on, um, constructing the new scorecard, and, you know, I want to make sure that the fields that we're capturing are going to allow you to
um, populate that…
you know, scorecard, if you will, and
flag any needs, questions, um, and status.
I think… I think we are…
good there until we… we have to dig further, but right now we're linking up.
MLQM and the file.
And then we'll kind of see what comes out of it.
But right now, I think we're okay, but I guess if anything comes up, we will reach out.
Okay, terrific. I appreciate you all, thank you. Sorry for going 2 minutes over.
Uh, no problem. Have a good one.
You as well. Bye-bye.